<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/gradfolio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/gradfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-24T17:53:48-04:00</updated><id>/gradfolio/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Maharshi Gor</title><subtitle>First Year Ph.D. CS Student | University of Maryland</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Home They Brought Her Warrior Dead</title><link href="/gradfolio/blog/2020/home-they-brought/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home They Brought Her Warrior Dead" /><published>2020-03-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/gradfolio/blog/2020/home-they-brought</id><content type="html" xml:base="/gradfolio/blog/2020/home-they-brought/">&lt;p&gt;Home they brought her warrior dead:&lt;br /&gt;
She nor swooned, nor uttered cry:&lt;br /&gt;
All her maidens, watching, said,&lt;br /&gt;
‘She must weep or she will die.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they praised him, soft and low,&lt;br /&gt;
Called him worthy to be loved,&lt;br /&gt;
Truest friend and noblest foe;&lt;br /&gt;
Yet she neither spoke nor moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stole a maiden from her place,&lt;br /&gt;
Lightly to the warrior stept,&lt;br /&gt;
Took the face-cloth from the face;&lt;br /&gt;
Yet she neither moved nor wept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rose a nurse of ninety years,&lt;br /&gt;
Set his child upon her knee—&lt;br /&gt;
Like summer tempest came her tears—&lt;br /&gt;
‘Sweet my child, I live for thee.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Home_They_Brought_Her_Warrior_Dead&quot;&gt;by Alfred Tennyson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Home they brought her warrior dead: She nor swooned, nor uttered cry: All her maidens, watching, said, ‘She must weep or she will die.’</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Jelly-Fish</title><link href="/gradfolio/blog/2019/jelly-fish/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Jelly-Fish" /><published>2019-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/gradfolio/blog/2019/jelly-fish</id><content type="html" xml:base="/gradfolio/blog/2019/jelly-fish/">&lt;p&gt;Visible, invisible,&lt;br /&gt;
A fluctuating charm,&lt;br /&gt;
An amber-colored amethyst&lt;br /&gt;
Inhabits it; your arm&lt;br /&gt;
Approaches, and&lt;br /&gt;
It opens and&lt;br /&gt;
It closes;&lt;br /&gt;
You have meant&lt;br /&gt;
To catch it,&lt;br /&gt;
And it shrivels;&lt;br /&gt;
You abandon&lt;br /&gt;
Your intent—&lt;br /&gt;
It opens, and it&lt;br /&gt;
Closes and you&lt;br /&gt;
Reach for it—&lt;br /&gt;
The blue&lt;br /&gt;
Surrounding it&lt;br /&gt;
Grows cloudy, and&lt;br /&gt;
It floats away&lt;br /&gt;
From you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://poets.org/anthology/poems-your-poetry-project-public-domain&quot;&gt;by Marianne Moore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Visible, invisible, A fluctuating charm, An amber-colored amethyst Inhabits it; your arm Approaches, and It opens and It closes; You have meant To catch it, And it shrivels; You abandon Your intent— It opens, and it Closes and you Reach for it— The blue Surrounding it Grows cloudy, and It floats away From you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Another sample post</title><link href="/gradfolio/blog/2019/some-more/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Another sample post" /><published>2019-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/gradfolio/blog/2019/some-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="/gradfolio/blog/2019/some-more/">&lt;p&gt;He had three simple rules by which he lived. The first was to never eat blue food. There was nothing in nature that was edible that was blue. People often asked about blueberries, but everyone knows those are actually purple. He understood it was one of the stranger rules to live by, but it had served him well thus far in the 50+ years of his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked at her little girl who was about to become a teen. She tried to think back to when the girl had been younger but failed to pinpoint the exact moment when she had become a little too big to pick up and carry. It hit her all at once. She was no longer a little girl and she stood there speechless with fear, sadness, and pride all running through her at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She considered the birds to be her friends. She’d put out food for them each morning and then she’d watch as they came to the feeders to gorge themselves for the day. She wondered what they would do if something ever happened to her. Would they miss the meals she provided if she failed to put out the food one morning?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">He had three simple rules by which he lived. The first was to never eat blue food. There was nothing in nature that was edible that was blue. People often asked about blueberries, but everyone knows those are actually purple. He understood it was one of the stranger rules to live by, but it had served him well thus far in the 50+ years of his life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A sample post</title><link href="/gradfolio/blog/2018/atticus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A sample post" /><published>2018-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/gradfolio/blog/2018/atticus</id><content type="html" xml:base="/gradfolio/blog/2018/atticus/">&lt;p&gt;Truly it was a great journey, and in it I met with many, whom to know was to love; but whom never could I see again; for life has not space enough; and each must do his duty to the security and well-being of the Redoubt. Yet, for all that I have set down, we travelled much, always; but there were so many millions, and so few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atticus said to Jem one day, “I’d rather you shot at tin cans in the backyard, but I know you’ll go after birds. Shoot all the blue jays you want, if you can hit ‘em, but remember it’s a sin to kill a mockingbird.” That was the only time I ever heard Atticus say it was a sin to do something, and I asked Miss Maudie about it. “Your father’s right,” she said. “Mockingbirds don’t do one thing except make music for us to enjoy. They don’t eat up people’s gardens, don’t nest in corn cribs, they don’t do one thing but sing their hearts out for us. That’s why it’s a sin to kill a mockingbird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a deep breath and listened to the old brag of my heart. I am, I am, I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that we can change the things around us in accordance with our desires—we believe it because otherwise we can see no favourable outcome. We do not think of the outcome which generally comes to pass and is also favourable: we do not succeed in changing things in accordance with our desires, but gradually our desires change. The situation that we hoped to change because it was intolerable becomes unimportant to us. We have failed to surmount the obstacle, as we were absolutely determined to do, but life has taken us round it, led us beyond it, and then if we turn round to gaze into the distance of the past, we can barely see it, so imperceptible has it become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most beautiful things in the world cannot be seen or touched, they are felt with the heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello babies. Welcome to Earth. It’s hot in the summer and cold in the winter. It’s round and wet and crowded. On the outside, babies, you’ve got a hundred years here. There’s only one rule that I know of, babies-“God damn it, you’ve got to be kind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Truly it was a great journey, and in it I met with many, whom to know was to love; but whom never could I see again; for life has not space enough; and each must do his duty to the security and well-being of the Redoubt. Yet, for all that I have set down, we travelled much, always; but there were so many millions, and so few years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes</title><link href="/gradfolio/blog/2017/sherlock/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes" /><published>2017-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/gradfolio/blog/2017/sherlock</id><content type="html" xml:base="/gradfolio/blog/2017/sherlock/">&lt;p&gt;“But if he is innocent, who has done it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ah! who? I would call your attention very particularly to two points. One is that the murdered man had an appointment with someone at the pool, and that the someone could not have been his son, for his son was away, and he did not know when he would return. The second is that the murdered man was heard to cry ‘Cooee!’ before he knew that his son had returned. Those are the crucial points upon which the case depends. And now let us talk about George Meredith, if you please, and we shall leave all minor matters until to-morrow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no rain, as Holmes had foretold, and the morning broke bright and cloudless. At nine o’clock Lestrade called for us with the carriage, and we set off for Hatherley Farm and the Boscombe Pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is serious news this morning,” Lestrade observed. “It is said that Mr. Turner, of the Hall, is so ill that his life is despaired of.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“An elderly man, I presume?” said Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About sixty; but his constitution has been shattered by his life abroad, and he has been in failing health for some time. This business has had a very bad effect upon him. He was an old friend of McCarthy’s, and, I may add, a great benefactor to him, for I have learned that he gave him Hatherley Farm rent free.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Indeed! That is interesting,” said Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, yes! In a hundred other ways he has helped him. Everybody about here speaks of his kindness to him.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“But if he is innocent, who has done it?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde</title><link href="/gradfolio/blog/2016/jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde" /><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/gradfolio/blog/2016/jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="/gradfolio/blog/2016/jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;“My will? Yes, certainly, I know that,” said the doctor, a trifle sharply. “You have told me so.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I tell you so again,” continued the lawyer. “I have been learning something of young Hyde.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large handsome face of Dr. Jekyll grew pale to the very lips, and there came a blackness about his eyes. “I do not care to hear more,” said he. “This is a matter I thought we had agreed to drop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What I heard was abominable,” said Utterson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It can make no change. You do not understand my position,” returned the doctor, with a certain incoherency of manner. “I am painfully situated, Utterson; my position is a very strange–a very strange one. It is one of those affairs that cannot be mended by talking.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jekyll,” said Utterson, “you know me: I am a man to be trusted. Make a clean breast of this in confidence; and I make no doubt I can get you out of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My good Utterson,” said the doctor, “this is very good of you, this is downright good of you, and I cannot find words to thank you in. I believe you fully; I would trust you before any man alive, ay, before myself, if I could make the choice; but indeed it isn’t what you fancy; it is not as bad as that; and just to put your good heart at rest, I will tell you one thing: the moment I choose, I can be rid of Mr. Hyde. I give you my hand upon that; and I thank you again and again; and I will just add one little word, Utterson, that I’m sure you’ll take in good part: this is a private matter, and I beg of you to let it sleep.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utterson reflected a little, looking in the fire.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“My will? Yes, certainly, I know that,” said the doctor, a trifle sharply. “You have told me so.”</summary></entry></feed>